I'm going to begin by reciting a poem.
سوف ابدا بقراءة قصيدة
"Oh beloved dentist:
"عزيزي طبيب الاسنان:
Your rubber fingers in my mouth ...
اصبعك المطاطي في فمي...
your voice so soft and muffled ...
صوتك ناعم جدا وخافت...
Lower the mask, dear dentist,
اخفض الكمامة يا ايها لطبيب العزيز
lower the mask."
اخفض الكمامة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Okay, in this presentation,
حسنا, في هذا العرض,
I'm going to be putting the right side of your brains
سوف يمر الجزء الايمن من عقولكم
through a fairly serious workout.
خلال تدريب جاد
You're going to see a lot of imagery,
سوف تشاهدون العديد من الصور,
and it's not always connected to what I'm talking about,
ولن تكون دائما مرتبطة بما اتحدث عنه.
so I need you to kind of split your brains in half
ماريده هو ان اقسم عقولكم الى نصفين
and let the images flow over one side
اتركوا الصور تنساب خلال نصف
and listen to me on the other.
واستمعو الي من خلال النصف الاخر
So I am one of those people
انا من أولئك الناس
with a transformative personal story.
لدي قصة شخصية تحويلية.
Six years ago,
قبل ستة سنوات,
after 20 years in graphic design and typography,
بعد 20 سنة في مجال تصميم الصور واساليب الطباعة
I changed the way I was working
غيرت الطريقة التي كنت اعمل بها
and the way most graphic designers work
والطريق التي يتبعها كل مصممين الصور
to pursue a more personal approach to my work,
لاضفاء طابع شخصي على عملي
with only the humble attempt
فقط بالمحاولة المتواضعة
to simply make a living doing something that I loved.
وبمنتهى البساطة للاستمرار في عمل الشيء الذي احببته
But something weird happened.
لكن حصل شيء غريب
I became bizarrely
اصبحت وبشكل غريب
popular.
مشهورة.
My current work
عملي الحالي
seems to resonate with people
وجد صداه لدى الناس
in a way that has so taken me by surprise
وتلقو عملي بنوع من المفاجأة
that I still frequently wonder
مما جعلني احاول التخمين
what in the hell is going on.
مالذي يحصل.
And I'm slowly coming to understand
وبدات ادرك شيئا فشيئ
that the appeal of what I do
ان الانجذاب الى ما اقوم بعمله
may be connected to why I do it.
قد يكون مرتبطا بالسبب الذي اقوم من اجله بهذا العمل
These days, I call myself a graphic artist.
في تلك الايام اطلقت على نفسي لقب فنانة صور
So where my work as a graphic designer
بالتالي عندما كان عملي هو مصممة صور
was to follow strategy,
كان علي اتباع خطة,
my work now
اما الان
follows my heart
فأنا اتبع قلبي
and my interests
واهتماماتي
with the guidance of my ego
وبارشاد من ذاتي
to create work that is mutually beneficial to myself and a client.
لانجاز عمل ذو منفعة متبادلة لنفسي ولزبوني
Now, this is heresy
الان,هذه هي هرطقة
in the design world.
في عالم التصميم
The ego is not supposed
"الانا" لا يفترض ان يسمح
to be involved in graphic design.
ادخالها في عالم تصميم الصور
But I find that for myself,
لكن وجدت ذلك في نفسي
without exception,
بدون استثناء
the more I deal with the work
كلما تعاملت مع العمل
as something of my own,
على كونه شيئ خاص بي
as something that is personal,
وانه شيئ شخصي
the more successful it is
كلما كان ناجحا
as something that's compelling,
كأنه شيء طاغي
interesting and sustaining.
مثير للاهتمام وصامد
So I exist somewhat outside of the mainstream
لذلك وجدت نفسي بطريقة ما خارج تيار
of design thinking.
التفكير التصميمي
Where others might look at measurable results,
حيث الاخرون ربما ينظرون لنتائج قابلة للقياس
I tend to be interested in more ethereal qualities,
صرت اميل بشكل كبير للصفات الغير ملموسة
like "Does it bring joy?"
اتساءل مثلا هل تجلب البهجة؟
"Is there a sense of wonder?"
هل تثير الاندهاش والتعجب؟
and "Does it invoke curiosity?"
وهل تثير الفضول؟
This is a scientific diagram, by the way.
هذا رسم تخطيطي , بالمناسبة.
I don't have time to explain it,
ليس لدي الوقت لشرحه.
but it has to do with DNA and RNA.
لكنه يتعلق بعلم الجينات دي ان اي و ار ان اي.
So I have a particular imaginative approach to visual work.
اذا انا لدي نهج تخيلي معين في الاعمال البصرية.
The things that interest me when I'm working
الاشياء المثيرة لاهتمامي عندما اعمل
are visual structure,
هو البناء البصري
surprise
المفاجأة
and anything that requires figuring things out.
والاشياء التي تجعلك تستنبط الافكار
So for this reason, I'm particularly drawn
لهذا السبب انا متجهة بشكل خاص
to systems and patterns.
الى النظم والانماط.
I'm going to give you a couple of examples of how my brain works.
سوف اعطيكم بعض الامثلة توضح كيف يعمل عقلي
This is a piece that I did for
هذه القطعة قمت بعملها
The Guardian newspaper in the U.K.
لصحيفة الجارديانز في بريطانيا
They have a magazine that they call G2.
لديهم مجلة يسمونها جي2
And this is for their puzzle special
وهذا العمل خاص لاحجيتهم الخاصة
in 2007.
بعام 2007
And puzzling it is.
وكانت بالفعل احجية
I started by creating a series of tiling units.
بدات بانشاء عدة وحدات مقطعة.
And these tiling units, I designed
وتلك الوحدات المقطعة, صممتها
specifically so that they would contain
بشكل محدد بحيث تحتوي على
parts of letterforms within their shapes
اجزاء من الحرف تشكل من خلالها اشكال
so that I could then
بحيث استطيع فيما بعد
join those pieces together
ربط تلك القطع معا
to create letters and then words
لعمل احرف ومن ثم كلمات
within the abstract patterning.
من خلال تلك النمط المجرد.
But then as well, I was able to
بالاضافة الى ذلك, كنت قادرة
just flip them, rotate them
على قلبها وتديرها
and combine them in different ways
وجمعها معا بطرق مختلفة
to create either regular patterns
لعمل نمط اعتيادي
or abstract patterns.
او نمط مجرد
So here's the word puzzle again.
اذا هذه احجية الكلمات مرة اخرى
And here it is with the abstract surrounding.
وهنا التجريد يحيط بالشكل
And as you can see, it's extremely difficult to read.
وكما تلاحظون ,من الصعب جدا قراءتها.
But all I have to do is
لكن كل ما علي فعله
fill certain areas of those letterforms
هو ملأ اماكن محددة من تلك الاحرف
and I can bring those words out of
وسأتمكن من اظهار تلك اكلمات
the background pattern.
من خلا النمط الذي في الخلفية
But maybe that's a little too obvious.
لكن قد يبدو ذلك واضحا.
So then I can add some color in with the background
لذلك يمكنني اضافة بعض الالوان في الخلفية
and add a bit more color in with the words themselves,
واضافة القليل من الالوان في داخل الكلمات ذاتها
and this way, working with the art director,
وبهذه الطريقة, وبالعمل مع المخرج الفني,
I'm able to bring it to just the right point
اصبح بامكاني جلبها الى النقطة الصحيحة
that it's puzzling for the audience --
بحيث تكون احجية بالنسبة للجمهور
they can figure out that there's something they have to read --
بحيث يلاحظون ان هناك شيئ يجب عليهم قراته--
but it's not impossible for them to read.
لكنه ليس بالشيء المستحيل قراءته.
I'm also interested in working with
انا مهتمة جدا بالتعامل مع
unusual materials
المواد غير الاعتيادية
and common materials in unusual ways.
او مواد اعتيادية بطرق غير اعتيادية
So this requires figuring out how to
وذلك بالتالي يتطلب مني ملاحظة كيف يمكن
get the most out of something's innate properties
استخراج الحد الاقصى من الخصائص الطبيعية للشيء
and also how to bend it to my will.
وايضا كيف اطوعه لاحتياجاتي
So ultimately,
بالتالي في نهاية المطاف,
my goal is to create something unexpected.
هدفي هو عمل شيئ غير متوقع.
To this end, I have worked in sugar
وتحقيقا لهذه الغاية, عملت على السكر
for Stefan Sagmeister,
لصالح ستيفان ساجميستر,
three-time TED speaker.
احد المتحدثين في تيد لثلاثة مرات
And this project began essentially
وبدا هذا المشروع اساسا
on my kitchen table.
على طاولة مطبخي.
I've been eating cereal for breakfast
كنت اتناول الحبوب على افطاري
all of my life.
افعل ذلك طوال حياتي.
And for that same amount of time,
وبالمقدار نفسه من الوقت
I've been spilling sugar on the table
كنت اسكب السكر على الطاولة
and just kind of playing with it with my fingers.
وكنت اللعب به بأصابعي
And eventually I used this technique
وفي نهاية المطاف استخدمت هذا الاسلوب
to create a piece of artwork.
لعمل قطعة فنية
And then I used it again to create
وثم استخدمته مرة اخرى لعمل
six pieces for Stefan's book,
ستة قطع لكتاب ستيفان.
"Things in My Life I've Learned So Far."
"اشياء تعلمتها في حياتي"
And these were created
وتم عملها
without sketches, just freehand,
بدون رسومات , فقط اليد الحرة
by putting the sugar down on a white surface
بوضوع السكر على سطح ابيض
and then manipulating it to get
ومن ثم معالجتها للحصول على
the words and designs out of it.
الكلمات والتصاميم.
Recently, I've also made some
مؤخرا,عملت ايضا بعض
rather highbrow baroque borders
بدلا من ذلك حواشي ذات صبغة تعبيرية
out of lowbrow pasta.
من المعكرونة
And this is for a chapter that I'm doing in a book,
وهذا لاحد الفصول التي اعمل عليها في احد الكتب
and the chapter is on honor.
والفصل على شرفه
So it's a little bit unexpected,
اذا , هذا الشيء نوعا ما غير متوقع
but, in a way, it refers
لكن, بطريقة ما, يدل
to the macaroni art
على فن المعكرونة
that children make for their parents
التي يعملها الاطفال لابائهم.
or they make in school and give to their parents,
او التي يعملونها في المدرسة ويعطوها لابائهم.
which is in itself a form of honor.
والتي هي بحد ذاتها مشرفة
This is what you can do with some household tinfoil.
هذا ما يمكنك عمله بورق القصدير المنزلي
Okay, well, it's what I can do with some household tinfoil.
حسنا, هذا ما يمكنني عمله بورق الالمنيوم المنزلي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm very interested in wonder,
انا مهتمة دائما بالتعجب
in design as an impetus to inquiring.
في التصميم كقوة دافعة للاستفسار
To say I wonder is to say
لتقول انا اتساءل اي لتقول
I question, I ask.
انا استفهم,انا اسأل.
And to experience wonder is to experience awe.
وبتجربة التساءل تجرب الخشية.
So I'm currently working on a book,
انا اعمل حاليا على كتاب
which plays with both senses of the word,
يتلاعب بحواس الكلمة.
as I explore some of my own ideas
كما وضحت بعض افكاري
and inquiries
و طلباتي
in a visual display of rather
بطريقة تصويرية
peacock-like grandeur.
فيها من عظمة الطاووس
The world is full of wonder.
العالم مليئ بالعجائيب
But the world of graphic design,
لكن عالم تصميم الرسوم
for the most part, is not.
في معظمه لا يحتوي على العجائب
So I'm using my own writings
لذك استخدم كتاباتي
as a kind of testing ground for a book that has
كنوع من ارضية الاختبار لكتاب يحتوي
an interdependency between word and image
على ترابط بين الكلمة والصورة
as a kind of seductive force.
كنوع من القوة الجاذبة
I think that one of the things
اعتقد ان هذا واحد من الاشياء
that religions got right
التي تحتويها الاديان
was the use of visual wonder
كان استخدام التساؤل التصوري
to deliver a message.
لبعث الرسائل
I think this true marriage of art and information
اعتقد ان هذا تزاوج حقيقي بين الصورة والمعلومة
is woefully underused in adult literature,
وهو ما يفتقده ادب الكبار بشكل يرثى له
and I'm mystified as to
وكنت مندهشة بسبب
why visual wealth is not more commonly used
كيف ان هذه الثروة التصويرية غير مستخدمة بشكل واسع
to enhance intellectual wealth.
لتعزيز الثروة الفكرية
When we look at works like this,
عندما ننظر لاعمال كهذه,
we tend to associate them with children's literature.
نتوجه لربطها بأدب الاطفال
There's an implication that ornamental graphics
هناك اشارات ضمنية بان الرسومات التزينية
detract from the seriousness of the content.
تقلل من جدية المحتوى
But I really hope to have the opportunity
لكن اتمنى حقا ان احصل على الفرصة
to change that perception.
لتغيير هذا المفهوم
This book is taking rather a long time,
هذا الكتاب استغرق وقتا طويلا
but I'm nearly done.
لكنني اوشكت على الانتهاء منه
For some reason, I thought it would be a good idea
لسبب ما اعتقدت انها قد تكون فكرة جيدة
to put an intermission
ان اضع استراحة
in my talk.
في كلامي
And this is it -- just to give you and me a moment to catch up.
فقط لاعطي نفسي واعطيكم فرصة لالتقاط الانفاس.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I do these valentines.
انجزت هذا بمناسبة عيد الحب
I've been sending out valentines
كنت ارسل معايدات عيد الحب
on a fairly large scale since 2005.
على مدا كبير منذ 2005
These are my valentines
هذه معايداتي
from 2005 and 2006.
من 2005 الى 2006
And I started by
وبدأت ب
doing just a single image like this
عمل صورة واحدة كهذه
and sending them out to each person.
وارسالها لكل شخص
But in 2007,
لكن في عام 2007
I got the cockamamie idea
بدات في الفكرة السخيفة
to hand-draw each valentine
بأن ارسم بيدي كل معايدة
for everyone on my mailing list.
لكل شخص في قائمتي البريدية
I reduced my mailing list to 150 people.
قلصت قائمتي البريدية الى 150 شخص
And I drew each person
ورسمت لكل شخص
their own unique valentine
معايدتهم الخاصة المتفردة
and put their name on it
ووضعت اسمه عليها
and numbered it and signed it and sent it out.
ورقمتها ووقعتها وارسلتها
Believe it or not, I devised this
صدقو او لا تصدقو ابتدعت هذا العمل
as a timesaving method.
كطريقة لحفظ الوقت
I was very busy in the beginning of that year,
كنت مشغولة جدا في بداية العام
and I didn't know when I was going to find time
ولم اكن اعلم متى سأجد الوقت
to design and print a single valentine.
لتصميم وطباعة معايدة واحدة.
And I thought that I could kind of do this piecemeal
وفكرت انه بامكاني عمل ذلك شيئأ فشيئأ
as I was traveling.
خلال تنقلي
It didn't exactly work out that way.
بشكل دقيق لم يتم العمل بتلك الطريقة
There's a longer story to this,
هناك قصة طويلة لذلك,
but I did get them all done in time,
لكنني قمت بأنجازها جميعا في الوقت المحدد
and they were extremely well received.
وكان قبولها بشكل ممتاز جدا
I got an almost 100 percent response rate.
حصلت على ردود بنسبة 100% تقريبا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And those who didn't respond
واولئك الذين لم يقومو بالرد
will never receive anything from me ever again.
لما يتلقو مني اي شيء مرة اخرى.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Last year,
في العام الماضي
I took a more conceptual approach to the valentine.
سلكت اسلوب اكثر خيالية
I had this idea that I wanted people
وصلت لفكرة انني اريد الاشخاص
to receive a kind of
ان يحصلوا على نوع خاص من
mysterious love letter,
رسائل الحب الغامضة
like a found fragment in their mailbox.
كقطعة وجدت في صندوق البريد
I wanted it to be something
اردتها ان تكون شيئا
that was not addressed to them
كما لو انها لم تكن موجهة لهم
or signed by me,
او قمت بتوقيعها
something that caused them to wonder
شيئ يجعلها يتساءلون
what on Earth this thing was.
ما المقصود من ذلك الشيئ
And I specifically wrote
وبالتحديد كتبت
four pages that don't connect.
اربع صفحات غير مترابطة
There were four different versions of this.
كن هناك اربع نماذج منها
And I wrote them
وكتبتها
so that they begin in the middle of a sentence,
بحيث تبدا في منتصف الجملة
end in the middle of a sentence.
وتنتهي في منتصف الجملة
And they're on the one hand, universal,
وهي من ناحية عمومية
so I avoid specific names or places,
حيث تجنبت تحديد اسماء او اماكن
but on the other hand, they're personal.
لكن من ناحية اخرى تبدو خاصة
So I wanted people to really get the sense that
حيث اردت فعلا ان يكون لدى الناس شعور انهم
they had received something that could have been
تلقوا شيئا يبدوا كأنه
a love letter to them.
رسالة حب لهم.
And I'm just going to read one of them to you.
وسأقوم بقراءة احداها لكم الان.
"You've never really been sure of this,
"لم تكن ابدأ متأكدا من هذا
but I can assure you that this quirk
لكنني بامكاني ان اؤكد ان ذلك هوس
you're so self-conscious of
انك واع له
is intensely endearing.
انه نوع من الحب العميق
Just please accept that this piece of you
ارجو قبول ان هذه القطعة منك
escapes with your smile,
هربت باببتسامتك,
and those of us who notice
وهؤلاء من لاحظوا
are happy to catch it in passing.
سعيدون بالتعبير
Time spent with you is like chasing and catching small birds,
إن الوقت الذي مضى معك كان اشبه بمطاردة وامساك الطيور الصغيرة
but without the scratches and bird shit."
لكن بدون خدوش ومخلفات الطيور"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"That is to say,
"لذلك اقول
your thoughts and words flit and dart,
افكارك وكلماتك اسرعت ووثبت
disconcertedly elusive at times,
هي بعيدة المنال بشكل مربك في بعض الاحيان,
but when caught and examined --
لكن حينما امسكت وفحصت--
ahh, such a wonder,
ااه مدهش
such a delightful reward.
ومكافأة لذيذة.
There's no passing time with you,
لا يوجد وقت يمضي معك
only collecting --
فقط نجمع--
the collecting of moments with the hope for preservation
جميع اللحظات في رغبه لحفظها
and at the same time release.
واطلاقها في نفس الوقت
Impossible? I don't think so.
مستحيل؟ لا اعتقد ذلك
I know this makes you embarrassed.
اعلم ان ذلك يشعرك بالخجل
I'm certain I can see you blushing.
انا متأكد اني استطيع رؤية حمرة الخجل
But I just have to tell you because
لك فقط علي ان اخبرك لانه
sometimes I hear your self-doubt,
في بعض الاحيان أستمع شكوك الداخلية
and it's so crushing to think
وانه من المحطم جدا
that you may not know how truly wonderful you are,
انك لا تعلم حقيقة كم انت رائع
how inspiring and delightful
كم انت ملهم ومبهج
and really, truly the most completely ..."
وحقيقتا وبصدق الاكثر كمالا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So Valentine's Day
اذا عيد الحب
is coming up in a couple of days,
سوف يحل علينا خلال الايام القادمة
and these are currently arriving
وتلك المعايدات تصل حاليا
in mailboxes all around the world.
الى صناديق البريد حول العالم
This year, I got, what I really have to say
في هذه السنة حصلت على ما يمكنني تسميته
is a rather brilliant idea,
فكرة عبقرية
to laser cut
التقطيع بالليزر.
my valentines
تقطيع معايداتي بالليزر
out of used Christmas cards.
مستخرجة من معايدات مسبقة الاستخدام
So I solicited friends
التمست من اصدقائي
to send me their used Christmas cards,
ان يرسلوا الي معايدات اعياد الميلاد المستخدمة
and I made 500 of these.
وعملت 500 منها
Each one of them is completely different.
كل واحدة منها مختلفة تماما
I'm just really, really thrilled with them.
انا حقا حقا اشعر بسعادة غامرة تجاهها
I don't have that much else to say,
ليس لدي شيئ اكثر لاقوله.
but they turned out really well.
لكن فعلا ظهرت جيدة
I do spend a lot of time on my work.
صرفت الكثر من الوقت على عملي
And one of the things that I've been thinking about recently
واحد الاشياء التي افكر فيها مؤخرا
is what is worth while.
مالذي يستحقه
What is it that's worth spending my time on
مالذي يستحق ان اصرف عليه وقتي
and my life on in this way?
وحياتي بهذه الطريقة؟
Working in the commercial world,
العمل في عالم الاعلانات التجارية
this is something that I do have to struggle with at times.
هذا شيء يستحق النضال من اجله
And yes, sometimes I'm swayed by money.
ونعم لقد انجذبت للمال
But ultimately, I don't consider that a worthy goal.
لكن في نهاية المطاف لا اعتبره شيء يستحق ان يكون هدفا
What makes something worthwhile for me
الذي يجعل شيئ ما مجدي بالنسبة لي
is the people I work for or with,
هو الناس الذين اعمل معهم ولاجلهم
the conditions I work under
الظروف التي اعمل تحتها
and the audience that I'm able to reach.
والجمهور الذي اريد الوصول اليه
So I might ask: "Who is it for?"
لذلك قد اسأل: لمن كل هذا؟
"What does it say?"
ماذا يمكنه ان يقول؟
and "What does it do?"
وماذا يفعل؟
You know, I have to tell you, it's really difficult
تعلمون, علي ان اخبركم انه كان فعلا صعب
for someone like me to come up on stage
على شخص مثلي ان ياتي على المسرح
at this conference
في هذا المؤتمر
with these unbelievably brilliant minds,
مع تلك العقول العبقرية بشكل لا يصدق.
who are thinking these
الذين يفكرون
really big-picture,
في تلك الصورة الكبيرة
world-changing, life-changing
تغيير العالم. تغيير الحياة.
ideas and technologies.
افكار وتكنلوجيا
And it's very, very common
ومن الشائع جدا
for designers and people in the visual arts
للمصممين والاشخاص العاملين في مجال الفن التصويري
to feel that we're
ان نشعر اننا
not contributing enough,
لا نساهم بشكل كافي
or worse, that all we're doing is
او بشكل اسوأ ان كل مانفعله اننا
contributing to landfill.
نساهم في طمر النفايات
Here I am; I'm showing you
الان اطلعكم على
some pretty visuals
بعض التصويرات الجميلة
and talking about aesthetics.
وا تحدث عن الجماليات.
But I've come to believe that
لكن وصلت لمرحلة الاعتقاد انه
truly imaginative visual work
حقاً ان الاعمال التصويرية الخيالية
is extremely important in society.
مهمة جدا للمجتمع.
Just in the way that I'm inspired
بنفس الطريقة التي استلهمها
by books
من الكتب
and magazines of all kinds,
والمجلات بكافة انواعها
conversations I have, movies,
الحوارات التي اجريتها,الافلام,
so I also think,
لذلك فكرت ايضا,
when I put visual work out there into the mass media,
عندما اضع عمل تصويري في اي من وسائل الاعلام,
work that is interesting, unusual,
ذلك النوع من الاعمال المثيرة للاهتمام, غير المعتاد,
intriguing,
مثير للفضول
work that maybe opens up that sense
ذلك النوع من الاعمال الذي لربما اثار حاسة
of inquiry in the mind,
الاستعلام في العقل,
that I'm seeding the imagination of the populace.
فانا بذلك اضع بذور الخيال لدى الجماهير.
And you just never know who
وانت لا تعلم من سيقوم
is going to take something from that
باستلهام اشياء من هذا العمل
and turn it into something else,
ويقوم بتحويله الى شيء اخر.
because inspiration
لان الالهام
is cross-pollinating.
يتم بشكل من اشكال التلقيح
So a piece of mine
فجزء من انتاجي
may inspire a playwright
قد يلهم كاتب مسرحي
or a novelist or a scientist,
او كاتب قصص,او عالم,
and that in turn may be the seed
وذلك بالتالي قد يبذر
that inspires a doctor
خيال طبيب
or a philanthropist
او فيلسوف
or a babysitter.
او جليسة اطفال.
And this isn't something that you can quantify
وذلك شيء لا يمكن تحديده بالكم
or track or measure,
اوقياسه.
and we tend to undervalue things in society
ونحن في المجتمع نستخف بالاشياء
that we can't measure.
التي لا نستيع قياسها.
But I really believe
لكنني حقيقة اؤمن
that a fully operating, rich society
انه اي مجتمع غني ونشيط
needs these seeds coming from all directions
يحتاج تلك البذور من جميع الاتجاهات
and all disciplines
وجميع التخصصات
in order to keep the gears of inspiration
في سبيل ابقاء عجلة الالهام
and imagination
والخيال
flowing and cycling and growing.
تسير وتدور وتنمو.
So that's why I do what I do,
لذلك اقوم بما اقوم به,
and why I spend so much time and effort on it,
وابذل فيه الوقت الطويل والجهد,
and why I work in the commercial, public sphere,
ولهذا السبب اعمل في مجال الاعلان والنطاق العام,
as opposed to the isolated, private sphere
على العكس من النطاق المعزول والخاص
of fine art:
للفنون الجميلة.
because I want as many people as possible
لانني اريد اكبر قدر من الناس
to see my work, notice it, be drawn into it,
ان يشاهدوا عملي, ويلاحظوه ,ويندمجو فيه
and be able to take something from it.
ويكون باستطاعتهم اخذ شيئ منه.
And I actually really feel that it's worthwhile
وانا اشعر حقية انه شيئ مجدي
to spend my valuable
ويستحق ما يصرف عليه من الغالي
and limited time on this Earth
والمحدود من الوقت على الارض
in this way.
بهذه الطريقة
And I thank you for allowing me to show it to you.
وانا اشكركم لاتاحة الفرصة لي لاطلاعكم عليه
(Applause)
(تصفيق)